foreign
thank you that was uh that was great you
guys applauded like my parents used to
every time I walked out of the house
he's gone he's finally gone I had a
unique childhood grown up I remember
when I was younger about the ages of
eight or nine my mother was very
protective of me and I thought it was
because she loved me turns out uh we
just didn't have medical
man I know for me I knew I was poor
growing up I was so poor I actually
loved losing teeth because that meant I
could get money from the Tooth Fairy
right like did you ever do that you ever
do the Tooth Fairy you lose a tooth put
it under the pill the next morning money
would be there right I decided when I
get older and I live in a nursing home
I'm gonna put money under my pillow and
hope tea pop out
like look I got one
nope just a Cracker Jack my bad my bad
but you know I'm actually afraid of
living in a nursing home when I get
older because I'm afraid of who I'm
going to be living with
have you guys seen my generation lately
[Laughter]
pray for me
we're all gonna look 95 but identify as
and we're still gonna be borrowing
somebody older's money somehow
foreign
itis and the blood clots
if I grew up poor and then for my career
choice I chose comedy so basically I am
not good at finances
I I had to do a bunch of odd end jobs
when I first started out comedy 12 years
ago tons of them like I used to be an
Uber driver because I was a middle child
and now feel the need to have my
personality rated every 10 to 12 minutes
[Music]
I did not like being an Uber driver
anybody ever be an Uber driver
if not okay if you don't know what it is
to to be an Uber driver or if you don't
know what it is to be in an Uber I'll
explain it to you this way basically uh
to get into an Uber you get in somebody
else's car and then you judge them
that's pretty much it I hated it when I
was an Uber driver but I got to tell you
now that I'm not a driver I love judging
other Uber drivers
like I like to treat each and every Uber
driver like a stepdad
foreign
I like to be like uh hey uh you got any
snacks
no hmm
my other driver had snacks
I think it's crazy we live in the
society where we can judge people for
any reason at all whatsoever right like
I just want to start going to people's
houses and raiding it on TripAdvisor
I want to be like don't go to my Aunt
Karen's house she has a litter box but
I've never seen a cat
foreign
[Music]
I I think people are are rude in public
nowadays too it's like I wish we could
start to rate those people online like
like for instance have you ever opened
the door for a stranger and halfway to
the door you realize that they don't
deserve it
anymore
so you just slowly close the door back
up when they're only inches away
I don't like when people cuss in public
like when people tell other people to go
to HD double hockey stick right so I
just tell people to go to Walmart
foreign
it's practically the same thing
the only difference is that uh hell is
known as a fiery place and if you ever
walk into Walmart you'll notice that
nobody there is hot
[Laughter]
does anybody here work at Walmart I
probably should have asked that question
first
good
yeah
I uh I I think if we started to um put a
rating to people's conversations it
would help people to stop saying stupid
stuff right like have you ever and we do
it too we absolutely do it have you ever
been in a conversation with somebody and
you forget their name
I've done that and if you've ever done
this is how I will help you for the rest
of your life if you're ever sitting
there and you're like I do not remember
this person's name do this it works you
just say excuse me um how do you spell
your name again
yeah it works almost every time until
they're like you don't know how to spell
Bob this is
like I'm sorry I thought there were
three bees I didn't know I didn't know
but I I think we started to rate
conversations it would help like have
you ever gone to the store with somebody
and you split up you want to meet back
up so you text hey where are you and
they reply I'm over here
what kind of an answer is that on the
phone
I'm over here that's not even an answer
I once went to a grocery store we split
up we were gonna meet back up I texted
hey man where are you he sent me his
location via Google Map
foreign
you know what pops up the address to the
building I'm in
what does he think it's gonna say melon
Isle
that's what he's supposed to say he's
supposed to say melon Isle
it's ridiculous I I think all of society
just gets us in a in a tizzy where we're
all frustrated and afraid of things and
you know I think fear comes from when
you're a kid like have you ever been
home alone and somebody knocks on your
door like for me that was the most
terrifying thing in the world because
nobody in my family is Liam Neeson
laughs
so if I got taken that was it
and like I know that I've heard people
say that you know um uh God did not give
you the spirit of fear right but uh
Jehovah's Witnesses have a couple times
oh the knocking I'm telling you I uh
that's not the deepest fear as a kid
though the deepest fear and I don't know
if anybody's I'm sure people have
related to this deepest fear ever as a
kid is watching a TV show or a movie and
your parent walking in because it
doesn't matter what TV show or movie
you're watching the moment your mom
walks in it's always at the most
inappropriate scene
in that TV show or movie and it doesn't
matter it doesn't even matter what
you're watching you could be watching
The Magic School Bus
the moment your mom walks in Miss
Frizzle starts dealing drugs
you're like Mom I swear this has never
happened
she's like
[Music]
I don't like scary movies I I can't
handle scary movies the same way people
can't handle spicy food you know those
friends even a little spicy is too spicy
they're like oh this is hot what is this
toothpaste
you can't handle toothpaste that's how I
am with scary movies and so I don't go
see him but my friends love them so a
while back I watched this movie and I
could not tell you what it's about
because my eyes were closed the whole
time
all I know is that it involves some
creepy kids I watched it Saturday night
I wake up Sunday morning to go to church
to repent
and I'm in the bathroom
alone or so I thought
all of a sudden this little kid I've
never seen before in my life
steps out of a stall and goes hi
I said um hi and he goes when I see
something scary
[Laughter]
I said not particularly
and he goes to the light switch and he
turns out the light
it turns it back on and he goes
I said um okay good good job and he goes
I want to see it again
I said I didn't want to see it the first
time
and it goes with light switch again and
turns it off turns it back on and goes
Roar and I said okay you're done and he
goes now now
one more time and it's gonna be the
scariest thing you've ever seen at that
point he turns the light off completely
it's complete darkness it's silenced for
a long time and I am convinced that the
creepy kids in the movie I saw the night
before have come back to haunt me
because I didn't watch their movie
so I'm in the corner and I'm 30 years
old I'm very secure I'll just tell you
I'm crying like a baby
and I walked in to use the bathroom but
I was about to do it again okay
and I'm just crying it's dark I don't
hear anything I'm assuming he's climbing
on the walls somewhere
[Laughter]
the saddest I've ever been all of a
sudden the light turns back on he's in a
different place and he goes Roar
apparently this was the scariest thing
I'd ever seen so I just go what's the
matter with you and I walked out of the
bathroom but then I've seen enough
movies that I'm like I gotta make sure
that this guy is in a figment of my
imagination so I stood by the bathroom
to follow him which legally do not do
okay
so I followed him and I figured out who
his dad is and his dad's really weird so
it makes a whole lot of sense
I'm just saying pastor kids are strange
good old Pastor kids
it's like I've always just been followed
with fear and and then when I was 18 is
when I started comedy started stand-up
comedy about 12 years ago and I had no
fear of it not working out
um because I just loved it so much and
that's when I realized that love
overcomes fear all day every day and
then I got married and I realized that
sometimes love and fear kind of go
together
and listen I love my wife she's my best
friend it's not that I'm afraid of
something that you husbands have never
told me round of applause if you're
married
go ahead
great great all of you married people
husbands I am mad at you because you did
not tell me something that I wish
somebody would have told me run out of
Applause if you're not married who's not
married
all right good three couples okay this
is awkward for you um here's I'm gonna
tell you something I wish they would
have told me which is this I'm gonna
lock eyes with you sir here it is when
you get married you are responsible to
keep everybody in your family alive
everyone your your wife keep her alive
your kids keep them alive animals alive
don't even think about a goldfish
do you know how hard it is to give CPR
to a goldfish named Nemo it's difficult
which is exactly why my dad was always
so stressed out because he had my mom
and four kids and he would constantly
shout things like don't stick your head
out the car window don't jump off the
stairs don't put your finger in the
light socket and that was all just to my
mom
scary stuff and now we've been married
three years so I learned to laugh more
than I do just be afraid of things and
my wife her and I are best friends she's
my my co-writer um we just have a blast
together but my single friends don't
believe it my single friends are always
like come on you guys gotta argue all
the time and no we've only had really
two fights so far one was because one of
us said that Star Trek was a terrible
show
and she was wrong
and the second fight was over a romantic
comedy which is the enemy to all men
you cannot compare yourself to a man in
a movie because he has music
like in a romantic comedy a man can end
an argument with one sentence he can
just be like I'm so sorry you're mad at
me but I didn't realize how beautiful
you are that doesn't even make sense
in real life a man can end an argument
that way half the time a man doesn't
even know when he's in an argument
he's like uh are you mad at me or
something
we haven't talked in weeks
I can't tell if we're in a fight or if
my wish came true
so we were it was over this movie called
Monster and lie but you ever see monster
in law
no none of you you've seen it
no you haven't
great here's the deal you are not
missing out
I'll give you a quick synopsis okay uh
Jennifer Lopez that's all you need to
know
it's not worth the watch there's a scene
in the movie where Jenny From the Block
is walking some dogs and while she's
doing it this guy goes up to ask her out
on a date and she goes you know what you
don't know anything about me you don't
even know the color of my eyes
just turns away just like that and makes
him answer now this is his answer you
have to imagine romantic music behind it
because he goes well at first
I thought your eyes were brown but then
I realized that they're green and then
when the sun sets it's almost Auburn
hold on
this man doesn't know he has no idea
what color her eyes are he listed three
different colors
but it sounds romantic because there's
music and she's turned away so she can't
see him throw away his man card
it's very lovey-dovey in the
in them in the living room my wife then
girlfriend it's important to know we're
not married yet so that you're on my
side
[Laughter]
she looks at me and she goes what color
are my eyes
there's a couple of things I think you
need to know about me uh number one I am
colorblind
actually I'm not but that's totally what
I told her
number two
um I am bad at tests like really bad at
tests
I I once I once got a D on a History
exam that I cheated on
okay my parents weren't even upset they
were just disappointed in me they were
like how did you do that you had the
answers on your hand like I'm sorry I
was nervous I didn't I didn't know so so
I got nervous when she asked me what
color are my eyes her eyes were closed
and this was my answer imagine beautiful
romantic music as well and I said
uh
uh Brown no not brown uh Brown no I just
said Brown uh
yellow no that's no that's not right
can't be yellow well your eyes are red
right now I'll tell you that
I failed I completely failed so then I
had to do the thing that a lot of guys
have to do in an argument I had to prove
to her that I was somehow right I was
like honey I said yellow at one point I
think I was right you might have
jaundice
that's in this argument head to the
hospital right now
we don't have time to argue when you got
the jaundice
by the way your eyes are blue
never once guessed it and it wasn't that
I didn't know like I knew her eyes were
blue but I just expected a more
complicated question like if she would
have asked me what's the one thing you
think about more than anything in the
entire world for her it's animals like
she thinks about animals so much that
she is emotionally attached just by
hearing a story about another animal
no no
[Laughter]
I'm gonna correct you there
laughs
the first time that her dad told her the
story of Jonah and the whale she just
burst it out into tears
it's not even about the whale
what are you talking about
and I like I like animals too but I just
don't think about them as much as she
does but that's the problem like I
walked home the other day and said honey
I have a surprise for you she goes is it
a kitty
I was like well I clearly walked in with
Chinese food so
[Music]
foreign
hey you guys came up with that punch
line not me
that's on you at this point
[Music]
[Laughter]
I love food by the way I love food I
just lost 50 pounds
yes oh thank you I appreciate that I'm
glad you guys applaud weight loss I'm
from the Midwest we do not applaud
weight loss
in the midwest uh I didn't realize until
I moved to the West Coast that uh that
there were cities and towns and states
that were very health conscious and I
moved to Arizona that's when I noticed
it because I went to a movie theater in
Phoenix Arizona and I watched somebody
order a small popcorn
small
I didn't even know small was a size like
I'm from Ohio you know Ohio the movie
theater isn't even about the movies it's
about the food
we have hoses of butter we spray on the
kids before the movie starts
everybody's slippery but we're happy
and sure in Ohio we do have popcorn size
small but it ends in the word bucket
we have small bucket large bucket
where's my accountability partner bucket
and then we have a family bucket which
is really just a wheelbarrow of popcorn
in your own personal butter hose
and that that's not enough for us I
don't know if anybody's parent ever did
this growing up but my mom would always
go oh we're going to the movies I'll get
my big purse laughs
right like the Moment the movie started
it was a scene from Mary Poppins
[Laughter]
Snickers snickerdoodles kitkats M M's
Gobstoppers oh who ordered the Chinese
food
I was like I did
and the best part is you could eat like
a pig at the movies because you're not
the one who has to clean it up
it's only some 14 year old worker at the
end of the night that's just like who
ate lo mein
and I I really what caused uh the weight
loss for me when I went out to Arizona
is I met friends that were very Fitness
focused and that's kind of how they LED
that's how they met me they were like I
hope you don't mind but we like to
exercise and have fun and they were
Liars
because we did not have fun like all we
did is exercise to this day all they do
with me is exercise like we're currently
training for a marathon why
like I'm pretty sure they're not my
friends
I'm pretty sure I'm at fat camp
[Laughter]
I haven't figured it out yet
but my friends these guys they showed me
things I'd never seen before from Ohio
things like gyms
anybody ever been to a Planet Fitness if
you have not yes okay if you have not
gone you need to go just to read the
names of the machines they have this one
machine
it does this
that is the most embarrassing machine
I've ever seen in my life
but do you guys know what they they call
this well they call this weird sorry sir
you know what they call this machine
they call it the hip abductor
did abduct your hip how does that happen
Hey fat little help
you like candy
get in the van
the Vania fan if you're gonna die
and the hip just wakes up in a warehouse
somewhere just like
when can I go home when you stop eating
cupcakes you fatty months later
someone's walking down the road they're
like oh Karen you look great oh thanks
it was the hippop doctor
completely abducted my hip
tortured it for a couple of weeks and
now it's a vegan
by the way this movement will end all
conversations
yeah
in case you ever want people to leave
you alone
[Laughter]
after I lost all the weight I had to
come up with diet rules never do a rule
they don't make they don't work they
they backfire every time like I love uh
cake a lot which side note I bet if
birthday cakes could talk I bet they'd
just blow and spit all over your face
and say how do you like it
I like the premise of that joke because
like why would a cake talk we don't know
foreign
but I created this rule where I told
myself I'm only going to eat cake at
weddings from now on that backfired real
quick do you know how easy it is to find
weddings on a Saturday
let's grab it and go that's what I love
about it
but I did like diets and everything like
that after to try to figure something
out and you know people always ask me
they're like oh okay how did how did you
lose that much weight is there one
secret to it I think we all know there's
not one secret like every person is
different everybody is different you
gotta find what works for you and what
works for me is workout videos
you know the ones that are like you're
doing great keep going I love those
because I learned something amazing
about them when they're encouraging you
they are not actually watching you
which means that you can do whatever you
want to do
and get encouraged
I recommend everybody tonight go home
open up that freezer grab your giant tub
of ice cream put peanut butter sprinkles
and birthday cake all over that bad boy
then you pop in that Richard Simmons DVD
and get encouraged
like you're doing great keep going I
will
don't stop I won't
dig deeper oh yeah
oh I got a freezer burn go past the burn
I'm trying go past the bird I'm trying
go past the bird just abduct my hair
thank you guys I'm Chris weinland
for watching my comedy special now is
the time where you can tip me and you
know you could tip me uh I don't know
the same price as a cup of coffee like
two three hundred dollars you know and
basically what this does is it helps
others uh to know who you like to see
online and also you know my whole family
gets to live and survive so go ahead and
tip me thanks so much